<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Myblog</title><link href="/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="//feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>/</id><updated>2010-09-28T09:21:00+05:30</updated><entry><title>Programming Vs. Scripting.</title><link href="//programming-vs-scripting.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-09-28T09:21:00+05:30</updated><author><name>haridas</name></author><id>//programming-vs-scripting.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="#id1"&gt;&lt;span class="problematic" id="id2"&gt;`|image0|`_&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was started to learn C programming language, I only know the term
Programming. After some time I learned about the Javascript and perl for
some internal projects, from there onwards I started to use the two
terms Scripting and Programming. I found some books of Javascript and
Perl describing about this at the beginning itself. But most of them are
not clearly specifying the difference correctly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think these terms were came  due to the difference of how these codes
are being running under the machine, ie; codes running under Interpreter
were normally called as Scripts and in Compilers were called as
Programs.The codes written in scripting languages are very simple to
understand when compared with compiled languages like C/C++ or Java. But
Java and other dynamic languages like Python have both interpretor and
compilers to run its codes, even though we call Python as Scripting
language. From this we can say that the naming hasn't any importance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are using these languages to solve or implement all types of logics.Here we
need to give importance to the problems and how well we can solve it
based on, which algorithm is being used, speed of the language, memory
usage, etc...The important thing is the &lt;cite&gt;Algorithm&lt;/cite&gt;, if it is optimal
then you can select any language that you like. Currently all major
Scripting languages like &lt;cite&gt;Python, Perl ,Ruby&lt;/cite&gt; and &lt;cite&gt;Tcl/Tk&lt;/cite&gt; are being
used for general purposes along with famous programming languages like
&lt;cite&gt;C/C++&lt;/cite&gt; and &lt;cite&gt;Java&lt;/cite&gt;.Other scripting languages are &lt;cite&gt;Php&lt;/cite&gt; (Web
based applications ), &lt;cite&gt;Lua Script&lt;/cite&gt; (Embedded language , very fast,low
memory foot print and also used for Game developments).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="conclusion"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can call the Computer Languages as Scripting language or
Programming language, but remember the Scripting languages can do any
thing and we should not consider it as a secondary one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="system-messages section"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Docutils System Messages&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="system-message" id="id1"&gt;
&lt;p class="system-message-title"&gt;System Message: ERROR/3 (&lt;tt class="docutils"&gt;/mnt/data/projects/workspace/myblog/pelican/pelican-blog/src/programming-vs-scripting.rst&lt;/tt&gt;, line 6); &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="#id2"&gt;backlink&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
Unknown target name: &amp;quot;|image0|&amp;quot;.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>