<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>haridas.in</title><link href="/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="//feeds/drafts.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>/</id><updated>2012-07-24T23:38:03+05:30</updated><entry><title>My Vim Story 2</title><link href="//my-vim-story-2.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-07-24T23:38:03+05:30</updated><author><name>haridas</name></author><id>//my-vim-story-2.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="section" id="how-to-setup-vim-as-an-ide"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How to setup VIM as an IDE.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the last article I described what thing made me to use VIM as my main
Editor. So on this article I'm trying to explaing how to setup Vim with
required plugins for different programming languages. I'm basically a Python
guy, so I'm concentrate on Python side. But most of them are applicable to
other programming langauages. You can find out more some of specific plugins
that helps to do more effective work with your favorite programming language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The default Vim installed with most of the Gnu/Linux destros are more than
enough to do our work. But if you wan't more eye catch look and feel and some
handy tools to do your work more quickly you need to install some Vim plugins,
font's, color thems etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Gnu/Linux Console based Vim has some limitation to show good font's and
colours. So you have to using GTK version of them Vim. Gvim. Gvim give you all
the super looking features to your vim with all Vim features. Just take a look
at my Console based Vim and Gvim screen shots.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="vim-on-kde-konsole"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Vim on KDE Konsole&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img alt="vim-on-console" class="align-left" src="/images/vim-console.jpg" style="width: 768px; height: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="gvim"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Gvim&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img alt="Gvim image" class="align-left" src="/images/gvim.jpg" style="width: 768px; height: 400px;" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the things we need to modify with the default Vim to get the above look and
feel, you have to change and update following things,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fonts and Syntax Coloring theme.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Setup plugin environment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add required plugins.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I configured my Vim with following Plugins&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="plugins"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Plugins&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1. MinbufferExplorar
2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>